odishaonline.gov.in 2017-12-31

# ::The Official Website of the Govt. of Odisha

Privacy Policy

Any time you visit a Web site, you may be providing information about yourself to the site's owner or operator. We at OdishaOnline respect and value your privacy and safeguarding your information is of utmost importance to us. We believe it is important that you know how we treat the information that we receive on the Internet and that information shared with us is safeguarded in accordance with the strictest standards of security and confidentiality both internally and externally.

At OdishaOnline we use information that we get from your visit to enable you to participate in and take advantage of the various programs and features presented on the OdishaOnline site and to make the OdishaOnline site useful and interesting to you. We do not use the information that we collect from the OdishaOnline site for any other purpose, nor do we share it with third party, except as specifically noted and with agencies, vendors, partners, or affiliates under contract with OdishaOnline. 

### Applicability of this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy applies only to the information that we collect on the OdishaOnline site and not to any information that we collect through other methods or sources, including sites owned or operated by our affiliates, vendors, or partners

Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our Service.

### On this Page Notice

  * What personal information we collect and how we use it
  * What are cookies and how does OdishaOnline use them
  * Sweepstakes, contests, games, and surveys
  * Email, mailing lists, and other services
  * Affiliated businesses and links to other sites
  * Our policy regarding selling or renting of personal information
  * Banners and other advertisements on OdishaOnline
  * Business transfers
  * Disclosure of personal information for legal purposes and protection of OdishaOnline and others

###  Choice

  * How you can decide what communication you'll receive from us

### Security

  * How we protect your personal information
  * Security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration Changes to the OdishaOnline Privacy Policy

###  Notice

What personal information we collect and how we use it When you visit the OdishaOnline site, we may capture your Internet provider's domain name (e.g. 'vsnl.com') and may also capture the route from where the visit came, and the paths taken as you move from page to page (i.e., your "click stream" activity).

Information we collect on the OdishaOnline site may be used to enhance this site in ways like these:

  * Arrange the Web site in the most user-friendly way
  * Customize your browsing experience of this Web site
  * Communicate special offers and featured items to you, if you choose to receive such notices
  * Respond to your question or suggestions

OdishaOnline only collects personal information that you choose to provide voluntarily when using or registering with the OdishaOnline site. "Personal information" includes information that can identify you, such as:

Name, address, phone number, email address, or company name Log-in information Bill / Biller information IP address (Note: For users who access the Internet from an Internet Service Provider (ISP), the IP address will be different every time you log on. OdishaOnline does not typically associate this information with any individual.) 

When you register or use OdishaOnline services you are required to provide data / information that OdishaOnline needs in order to create your OdishaOnline account and fulfill our service commitment to you. This is collected on the registration form and from the Biller / bill details provided by you. These details are necessary to service your account.

While you can browse our site without providing personal information, you will need to input certain personal information as indicated on specific pages of our site in order to take advantage of certain features, such as requesting updates on promotional offers or participating in special programs.

Like any business interested in attracting and offering the highest quality of service to clients, OdishaOnline may, from time to time, send you e-mail and other communication to tell you about OdishaOnline services, features, functionality and content or seek voluntary information from you. OdishaOnline may also on occasion ask you to voluntarily submit information about other people. For example, you might be asked for the name and email address of people you know so we can inform them about a sweepstakes, contest, or other promotion or program offered on the OdishaOnline site. This information is kept completely private and confidential. It is aggregated with that of all other clients to provide us with the ability to tailor our services and content to those individuals most interested in our service. 

### What are cookies and how does OdishaOnline use them?

Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make the Web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and many major Web sites use them to provide useful features for their customers. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a Web site if you do so. 

### Sweepstakes, contests, games, and surveys

From time to time, OdishaOnline may conduct sweepstakes, contests, games or other promotions, and also conduct surveys through the Web site. If you choose to participate—unless otherwise noted in the applicable rules, terms and conditions, or disclaimers—we may use the information you provide in connection with the administration of the applicable promotion, including for selection and notification of sweepstakes or contest winners and for creation of new promotions, and/or to publish survey results in aggregate on the site.that run on OdishaOnline may be sponsored or cosponsored by entities / services other than OdishaOnline. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared.

Except where necessary to administer a sweepstakes, contest, game or other promotion, or survey, unless you have otherwise agreed or unless required by law, we will never permanently record or publish any response you give connected to your name or address. We will hold these responses only as anonymous statistics

### Email, mailing lists, and other services

When you request information or services, we use your email address and any other information you give us to provide you with the information or services you've requested, including sending transaction confirmations, acknowledgements and alerts. Mail confirming your transactions or any changes to your account information will be sent as per OdishaOnline operating policy and with a view to enhance the security of the service offering.

In respect of other information or services sent to your email address, we will continue to provide these until you ask us to stop (by using the "unsubscribe" instructions provided on each email and/or the Web site where you signed up and/or as we otherwise provide), or until the information or service is no longer available. We will not use your email address or other information to provide you with any unsolicited message or information (unless the message or information is part of the service you are requesting).

### Affiliated businesses and links to other sites

We work closely with our affiliated businesses, vendors and partners, many of which may have links within the OdishaOnline site. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the OdishaOnline site to another Web site, this Privacy Policy no longer applies. Your browsing and interaction on any third party's Web site, including any site that has a link on OdishaOnline is subject to the rules and policies of that site. We encourage you to read the rules and policies of the sites you visit to better understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

### Our policy regarding selling or renting of personal information

Our policy is simple: we do not sell or rent your personal information to any third parties under any circumstances, except in the event of a bankruptcy or reorganization, or a sale of all or substantially all of our assets, as further provided below.

### Agents

We may employ other companies and individuals to perform services on behalf of OdishaOnline, such as (1) administering special reward or other programs affiliated with OdishaOnline, or sweepstakes, contests and other promotions, (2) sending emails, (3) providing marketing assistance, and (4) analyzing data. Such companies and individuals will have access to the personal information necessary to perform their services, but will not be permitted to use it for any other purpose.

### Banners and other advertisements on OdishaOnline

The OdishaOnline site may displays banners and other advertisements that may be placed by third parties. Such advertisers may collect non-personal information (meaning, information that is not identifiable to any individual) when you click or scan one of their advertisements, by placing cookies on your computer or by using other technology. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any such third parties. In addition, we may share aggregate information about our visitors to third-party ad servers or potential advertisers in order to provide advertisements on OdishaOnline about products and services that may be of interest to you.

### Business transfers

If a third party acquires all or substantially all of our assets, your personal information, aggregated information, and any other information that we have collected on the OdishaOnline site may be transferred to such third party as part of our business assets. Also, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, all such information may be considered one of our assets and may be sold or transferred to third parties.

If a third party acquires all or substantially all of our assets, your personal information, aggregated information, and any other information that we have collected on the OdishaOnline site may be transferred to such third party as part of our business assets. Also, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, all such information may be considered one of our assets and may be sold or transferred to third parties.

We reserve the right to share your personal information with third parties if required to do so by law, or if we believe such action is necessary in order to: (a) conform to the requirements of the law or comply with legal process served upon us; (b) protect or defend our legal rights or property, the OdishaOnline site, or our users; or (c) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or violations of the terms and conditions for using the OdishaOnline site.

### Choice

How you can decide what communication you'll receive from us If you choose to receive them, we may periodically send you email messages describing updates, new features, or promotional offers related to this Web site. You can choose to stop receiving this email at any time. Simply follow the instructions included in your email, or send a reply stating your request.

### Security

How we protect your personal information

The security of your personal information is very important to us, and we are committed to protecting the information we collect.

Your OdishaOnline account information is password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your OdishaOnline account information by using your OdishaOnline User ID and password

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, OdishaOnline has put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure all Personal Information that OdishaOnline collects online. To learn more about our security click here

We recommend that you do not divulge your password or your secret question and answer to anyone. OdishaOnline will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your OdishaOnline account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

OdishaOnline uses firewalls and Secure Socket Layers for all personal data we collect from you. We also employ many different security techniques to protect personal data against loss, misuse, alteration, and unauthorized access. But we cannot guarantee perfect security of your personal information.

### Customer Service and Recourse Changes to the OdishaOnline Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was revised and posted on.OdishaOnline reserves the right to change, modify, or amend this policy at any time and post those updates on this page. You are responsible for revisiting this page to review our Privacy Policy updates. Please also read over the OdishaOnline Terms and Conditions.

### How to contact OdishaOnline regarding your concerns and questions

Please note that whenever you submit any information to us in connection with any services related to the OdishaOnline site, you consent to let us process this information in India as necessary to provide the services in which you are participating.

you have any questions, comments, criticisms, or complaints about OdishaOnline's Privacy Policy and/or the way it affects you, please feel free to email us at odishaonline@oesl.in Or write to us at:

_Customer Care - (Privacy Policy Issues)  
Odisha e-Governance Services Limited,  
OCAC Building, Acharya Vihar Square,  
Bhubaneswar-751013  
_

### Additional Information

If at any time you believe that OdishaOnline has not adhered to these privacy guidelines, please notify us by email at odishaonline@oesl.in and we will we will resolve it and take any remedial action as we reasonably determine in our discretion and in accordance with applicable laws.
